# AGUSTIN GUERRA

888-858-6716 | agustinguerra@ufl.edu | LinkedIn | Website

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly motivated engineering professional with 5+ years of experience in the transportation industry and +4 years of research experience in traffic engineering. Committed to providing high-quality service focusing on innovation, safety, sustainability, operational performance, diversity, equity, and inclusion. Currently conducting research about optimization of traffic operations considering connected and automated vehicles (CAVs).

#### EDUCATION

**PhD Candidate in Civil Engineering** 

University of Florida **MS in Civil Engineering** University of Kansas **BS in Civil Engineering** 

Universidad Tecnologica de Panama

Aug. 2019 - Expected May 2023 Gainesville, FL Aug. 2017 - May 2019 Lawrence, KS Mar. 2008 - May 2013 Panama, PA

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Expertise: Transportation Engineering, Statistical Analysis, Operation Research, Machine Learning

Programming and Statistical Languages: Python (+3 years), R (1 year)

**Software**: MS Office, SPSS

**Developer Tools**: Github, Visual Studio Code

Scientific Python Libraries: Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, CPLEX, sci-kit learn, TensorFlow, Selenium, webdrivermanager, xml

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Graduate Research Assistant**

University of Florida

Aug. 2019 - Present Gainesville, FL

- Develop optimization algorithms in Python for arterials considering CAVs capabilities
- Assist in the implementation of optimization algorithm for isolated intersections
- Facilitate the coordination of projects' activities to meet deadlines
- Formulated different optimization models to reduce intersections' delays (LP, IP, MILP)
- Developed heuristic methods to reduce delays in arterials (search-based algorithms)
- Developed a Python-based data pipeline to extract CAVs trajectories from connected vehicles
- Worked on data prepossessing, and data imputation
- Evaluated machine learning algorithms to estimate the occurrence of future crashes

## **Highway & Traffic Consultant**

WSP

May 2019 - Aug. 2019 Panama

- Provided safety assessment for roadways, interchanges, and intersections
- · Developed geometric design proposals

### **Highway Engineer**

Nov. 2012 - Aug. 2017

Panama

Louis Berger • Led the development of highway design projects. Project portfolio comprises several projects in

the Latin American region (Panama, Colombia, Honduras, and Peru) adding up to \$3 billion in construction amount

- · Coordinated with different departments (geotechnical, hydraulic, and pavement) to meet deadlines
- Facilitated the establishment of a new business unit in Bogota, Colombia
- Led and mentored a design team of 4 people

## LEADERSHIP/INVOLVEMENT

<b>Founding Member and Chair of the IEEE-ITSS Student Chapter</b> : Led the efforts to establish an IEEE Student Chapter branch of the ITSS at the University of Florida	2022 – Present
ITE University Chapter Vice President: Coordinated student seminars and ITE activities	2021 – 2022
<b>Student Representative at the UFTI Internal Steering <u>Committee</u></b> : Promoted engagement activities between industry professionals and students	2020 – 2022
<b>Media Manager at KU Fulbright Student <u>Association</u></b> : Led dissemination of activities promoted by the Fulbright Student Board, 2018	2018 - 2019

# FELLOWSHIPS & AWARDS

ITS Florida Anne Brewer Academic Scholarships: Awarded by the ITS Florida Chapter	2022
Fulbright Fellowship: Awarded by the U.S Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs	2017
<b>Global Best Project</b> : Awarded by the <u>ENR</u> for the Coastal Beltway project in Panama	2015
Professional Societies	
<u>IEEE</u> : Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers	2022 – Present
<u>IEEE-ITSS</u> : IEEE Intelligent Transportation Systems Society	2022 – Present
ASCE: American Society of Civil Engineers	2022 – Present
ITE: Institute of Transportation Engineers	2019 – Present

# **REFERENCES**

**Lily Elefteriadou, PhD**: Barbara Goldsby Professor, University of Florida **Aurora Izquierdo**: Civil Structural Engineer II, WSP

Juliana Canas: Senior Advisor, First Climate

Julio Aysa: Env./Social and Governance Lead Officer, IDB

elefter@ce.ufl.edu Aurora.Izquierdo@wsp.com juliana.canas-vanegas@firstclimate.com jaysa71@yahoo.com.mx